Let's
begin I lose something and others
receive
criticism from
me you feel They
gain something people who criticize they
want something the one who criticizes
me I lose
something you need to try to stop this
feeling
when someone criticizes you when you
try to improve yourself then in fact
you
win and then the final
words then ours will change will
change a lot the
text we have been studying this text for about 11
years
this morning we will finish a very large
section he says Listen when people
criticize you the critic and the one who is criticized will
both die anyway
these
years
criticized like a
dream you die as if waking up from a
dream you know how the first few minutes you
wake up you
feel something happened in a dream someone
hurt you in a
dream for
5 minutes you think someone hurt me
drink coffee SU
is forgotten
also everything will die and in 5
[music]
minutes you will not
remember so Why are you so
serious Personally, I think if you are a
student you should walk around with such a stupid
smile all the time
[music]
someone said that you are very stupid
made a lot of mistakes  This is what
I'm worried about
in these
teachings I think it's
1921 inside the
teaching teacher pon
pota k was one of my
teacher's teachers he said listen
to the
day when all the people in this room are already
dead and all All the criticism all
the worries all the problems no one will be
Who would remember all this
and now the
truth of the
teachings Who would live one after another they all
died when the last one died No one
remembers who
criticized whom we say remember my words
means
that this will happen in this
room remember we we went lamrim in
right Faith there was this
guy He
died yesterday Then there will be a
second and after 10 no one wants to talk about
it
and then everyone will
die and all this worry about
criticism no one will even remember
those who remembered are already
dead and it's like a
dream we all say goodbye in another
place Maybe we will remember criticism for 5 minutes
then we will forget everything And even our
closest ones our family we will replace
everything
Don't let someone's criticism waste your
time you have very little time
here someone called me
stupid I say yes you're right I'm stupid what's
next I don't worry about
it do something beautiful you don't have
time Don't waste time you
can say thank you
very much just
forget only if there is no
truth in what they said and then you
can
work news
We have reached the tenth day
[music]
Hurray Once a year or twice a year we
reach the one day in the original
teachings all the teachings took 24 days when
we first started 14 years
ago I first taught the last two
days because on those days it began how to
meditate remember it was in the press in the
hotel where there were
bed bugs cut out there were these
bugs they taught meditation everyone
itched a little it has improved since then
completed the last two
days a total of 24 days
we reached the
first one today almost
finished Why did I teach the last part at the
beginning
this is the
meditation part And you need to meditate on this
whole
book I At first the
meditation was here bed
bugs I will repeat this
part from another
book the greatest  Buddhist book
ever written in
Tibet big Steps on the
Path his book is a 1000
pages 500 pages about emptiness and how
[music] to
meditate this will be
dessert We will do this in about 2 years we will
stop talking about other
things
[music]
traditionally When a teacher in Tibet
begins to teach a new
Day they a
But revise the previous day
so we will go through the
previous
day the
first first part is an ancient tantra
from
Ma
he says try to block
the road to a lower
birth and we have a database of John Bre
12 ml
pages I can find this quote in 3
seconds of
the verse there are capital
letters This is a whole
verse it means I
bow I
bow
he says that this can help you to
avoid the realm of ODO and the highest
realm it can lead you to a city
where no one ages dies so
I
bow I bow neither this is how
he if you do not know the whole verse you will not
understand what he is talking about Therefore we are
very lucky that we have
means Every morning when  we are starting a
training You must ask yourself Why am I
here I am trying to
do I flew over Laha 2 days
ago
[music]
and how long will we have to go to the
hotel and you can see how thousands of cars
drive along the
road and then you should think about why
I am traveling for a
year people in this class today will all
disappear
there is a city of people that I was watching The plane's
overhead disappeared too They
will all go to another
[music]
place when it says that 100 years
ago there were people in Khala but now they are
not when you are on the plane you look at all the
cars You must remember why you
come to Haru
I want to help all the
people how many people in 5
[music]
mil they have no idea what
will come They try very hard
try not to think about it but they will all
die everyone will need to go somewhere that's why
I am going to direct
faith I will learn So
help them every day every
morning we
begin think about all the people you
want to
help do you know at least something about how to
die you are already a very valuable
person because
steel no one else
knows every person
here  You are an excellent
teacher. We started a university.
Why did I study at a
prince
publicly, some American newspaper said it was a
better
university, but they didn't even
teach me how to
die for 5 minutes. That's why we need to be
taught, well, the Master of
Death.
How to
die properly. We thought that this new
university was the best. It's a real
university, better than Harvard,
better
than where I got my PhD.
It's the oldest university in South and
North America here in
Mexico. But their university is
better because
there you can also learn how to
die while you're getting an
NBA. We combine
two
real universities. You'll learn Google Analytics. How
to sell
things. It's a full university, and we have
many foreign and American
teachers. There will be
real real
training. We will also have a specialty
in
death.
How to take care of big
things. And it's going to what we call
seven
[music]
points. There is a structure that you haven't
noticed yet, because
we teach lo.
John, we study women. How to develop a kind
heart, and there are seven
parts to this. Many people take pictures, probably
thinking that I will
give away money. This proves that my teaching system is
correct.
In case I give away money.  100
dollars
tomorrow Let's go through all these
se I will give 100 dollars tomorrow to three
people these are the
seven ancient
ancient teachings Ola
John First is
preparation number
two is how to chi
state number three How to use
problems as a path to enlightenment
what section are we in
now
how to use problems to become bu
part number
four This is sa how to practice for the rest of your
life
there are 18
meditations not very long you can do it in a
minute
and the last days we will do this
[music]
zam need to fly back to
Arizona in the evening
My wife is having knee surgery I need
[music]
Prepare We have
training
with and they will teach you
number
[music]
me until we meet again In November
or
October we will continue to study this
also
simplicity of
medicine in September
in now until
then you will do 18
meditations don't worry each of them
takes 5
minutes and we will study them the last few
days and number four
until the end of your
life You can use these
[music]
18 you will need to study the last day
fifth
stage I'm trying to make a green smoothie because
I think my hair will grow but it's
growing in the wrong
places number
five How do you know
you've succeeded in la
jong
how do you know you have this
kind
heart how does it
feel number p
number a promise you can make
about a kind heart
we
then final
advice
these are
classic teachings on la jong and we are in the
middle number
three you tell me List se of them
tomorrow three people I'll give you
$100 I'm trying to unload my
backpack for the way back
let's do It's
simple
first
preparation let's do seven words it's
$15 per
word preparation
first
two the
practice itself number three
problems as a
path number
four meditations for the rest of your
life number
five How did you know How do you know you
have a kind heart number
six a promise you
can just say a promise
and number
seven
tips Gentlemen Santiago he
writes down that he will earn a lot of money
I
like Thank you for a nice t-shirt
[music]
Don't forget that he is starting a new day of
teachings and don't forget that these teachings come
in seven
parts
teacher  listed them again as he
started a new
day when these first ones were And what about the
first two?
Preparation of the
[music]
practice itself
says that we need to watch this
habit of
only taking care of ourselves,
also watch the habit where we don't
take care of others and we need to change their
places first, take care of
others,
what you want will happen If you are first of all, the
pose says that
we take away other
people's problems, they come up and say I
Study I
want to study secret
Buddhism here he says if you want to study
secret
Buddhism, stay after class and
secretly clean the
toilet in the kitchen, wash the dishes
secretly This is a real secret
Diz,
he kind of does the
latter Don't forget that taking and
giving can
be you can do this during
your I as I age I start to
hurt there is
one of the pleasures that
awaits you then the elbow starts to
hurt and It is useful for me and I like to go
to the gym
and
swim, you
can kind of include something else in
GU I walk on the road I do
yoga I stand on my
head  I lift weights a little, then I
do my thing. It's funny, everyone in the gym is looking at you,
and you're doing this
[music].
Maybe you can do
[music]
like taking away other people's problems and
giving them
happiness. You can sit in the gym and do
it for everyone. They'll just think you're
some weird guy. Maybe you
really are a weird
guy again
[music].
11. You don't have to repeat them, because
you already
know them. I bribed you so you'd
remember. I'm interested.
11.
These. We've already finished. Because at the beginning, I was
wearing
all
these
instructions. Then he talks about the
mandala. He talks about the secret
mandala. There was a secret
mandala that was
called. The
King said, "Do it the same way."
He doesn't say how
exactly they used it. They went through
something very
long, and it's a prayer that was taken
from the
lotus flower of
1973 or
Seche. I went to study there,
and he said, "I will study
English." He spoke to me in
English, paid for his lesson in
Washington, D.C.,
to study
English, and I came to
live. You can be my driver and
my
port.  We can go to Washington together.
Eme,
it was part of the
Sri Lankan embassy. There was a place for monks where you
could
live. I lived with him and helped him
cook. The guys from they came and asked, '
You're a
monk,'
and I said, 'No, I just started studying
Buddhism.' I don't know anything.
[music]
I was told you can't
stay in this
building then. I said, 'Where should I
go?' across the street. Ask if you
can
stay there. No, they didn't give me permission to
stay there. Well, you have to wake up at 3
a.m. and beat this drum for 34
[music]
hours. He
said, '
Okay.' I was very devoted. I said, 'I
need to ask my
teacher, a Japanese monk.' He said, 'Do
n't give it
back. Can I wake up at 3 a.m. and
beat the
slave? If you don't do this, you'll be
kicked out.' Yes, I
did it while I was doing it.
This is the first position of the day.
[music]
lotus and they have a very deep
meaning. This is the practice we need to
do here. We have a
picture. This is a library. I
think
this is a library in
[music]
Mongolia. The Mongolian National
Library.  For 75 years they were not supposed to
practice
religion I think about 15 monks were
killed in one
day
and other people They buried books to
hide
them We went there in
1997 we started digging up all these
books and so far we have found
books and the library it is very
beautiful and John bdi was there last
week
He is collecting all this
money to preserve all these books and
digitalize
them
we have completed 12 million pages
it took several years it was
very hard work and it is available for
free
online we are almost 7% finished I think
it will take another 50
years I hope that John bdi will
do his
yoga because he still needs to
finish some things
there is a practice that we do
when we go to the library we do
a little
meditation imagining that the work is
finished for a little
we
celebrate the
Mongolian
word correctly It is
horse milk and you don't put it in
the refrigerator and it would ferment and then you
drink it you don't have to
do that
but we
celebrate  advanced
holiday we celebrated the day when we
completed 300,000
books we celebrated a little earlier
and it's a very cool
practice we have
[music]
a little and then you
meditate and you imagine that the whole
project is
finished and everything is online and everything is
translated and it will take 700 years to
translate we have a
team of translators 12
translators we have been working for 7 years we
have completed about 100 books now
every 500
pages are very
difficult we
did
lessons each of them is very
[music]
difficult and each of them was 5 hours of
lessons and it was very difficult because you had to
wake up at 4
am to come to morning classes
for
Asia Arizona in the wrong
place
between also Bahara
also morning for Europe evening for
Asia we had to do a party late in
the evening early in the
morning it was hard and even young
translators lost
their one class classes one after another
very deep
classes we have a new
offer starting in
October I want to do it differently
[music]
we will meet once a  week
throughout the whole
year so that I can
sleep we do 3 hours once a
week there will be Monday
evening Monday
evening 3 hours of very deep
studies we will do throughout the
whole year
and we have 12
books of which it is simply
impossible so I have another
proposal on Monday
evening we
will do two possible books and one
impossible there
will be difficult studies and one
impossible And this is Monday morning in
Asia and I will continue throughout the
whole year if we have such a
program we are rushing to
MRI on the contrary
in a
five-year course when I was in third
third grade my
teacher grabbed me and said
today you will not go to
class You will go to classes in the
fifteenth
year I am
sure he waved
his
rosary and I say yes Then I want I
want to
go and I sat in
the back I did not understand a single
word for almost 2
hours I did not
understand anything I came
home He asked how
classes were I said I did not understand a word
they were
talking and he said excellent
[music]
Semina this seminar will disappear in 12 years
and that's what
happened in the
fifteenth year everything was simple you
know what I'm
talking about in  Monday
evening will be the
evening of confusion you do not sing anything but
just open yours and grandpa will plant
Sam and in a few
years it will grow this is a very beautiful
way of
learning you need to put on shoes how to
fight you understand what happens in
class there is a special mental
state Lama by
seed I don't
understand anything what you are talking about Well I'm
open That's probably why such
hair just Be
open
I really want you to come to these
classes if you don't have money Just
tell
Nick we don't really take money we just
take money for technical
support if you don't have money tell Uncle
Nick that Uncle Michael said you
can come just
Come Wherever I am in the
world Monday
evening we will rvm everything and we will have 3 hours of
ancient
books and I really want you to
come Why do I say
Bib
heart there is a
tradition
sometimes when you do your
[music]
meditation that all the work is already
finished And in the
case
I go to 300 years of
VD that
the books are already
completed in Mongolia this
week Novo he found another
library there is more  300,000
books and he found a
sponsor
we can
start the
lotus prayer when you act like you're already a
bu pretend that everyone in the room is too
Buddha
one of the first classes I
attended with my
teacher a very small little
apartment he taught for a very long time in an
abandoned
bank under the Brooklyn Bridge
we plastic bags from the
branch it's hard to hear because it was under
the bridge asked someone has a
question
he said to me ska we must practice until
we become bumi
said correctly Yes this is why
here Sva what
happens then talk didn't
think and said after bu get together
program listening to each other everyone teaches
What could be more beautiful than
this sometimes when you in such
classes cheskaya
practice imagine that everyone is already a
bu and even the Last person is also a
bu
that this is the best thing we can
do even after M
[music]
law do after they are already
Buddhas they just lead the program because it's
just fun to talk about it
clearly and Teach in this place
says Imagine that all the work is already
completed that 600,000 bu books  John's watch is
already
completed that everyone
already especially
children
[music] do
you think that we're already
finished, is it
just enjoyment?
Chust
over
time I like
the picture it was filmed many years ago when
I was in
[music]
diamond I learned How to cut Alma
If you are between your fingers Look you
will see
Almada you see
this I say what you thought about the Diamond
Way and Secret
Buddhism
name
Diamond
Way the essence of the Diamond
Way achieving the
goal that you pretend that you are already there
is Diamond
still
zhu the essence of the secret teaching of
Buddhism is
already
finished creating that everyone is already a
Buddha this is the
path to the
present that the result
becomes a tree become
already
Buddha this is the best way to achieve
this if you are interested in the Diamond
Way or you and your
wife Secret Buddhism
this is su
secret pretend that everything is already
completed and the person who sits next
to you is already
Buddha This is the best way to
make it
happen when you see a
Diamond you need to
think about it grandfather cuts a
Diamond you need to think Man  right next to me
already
bu I spend time with
adults
next
[music]
picture
then holiday
that sometimes I with my dear wife
Veroni we go to
dinner the best
together oh says why
what occasion on what
occasion can you tell because we already
bu subm
[music]
from some of my
friends their books
understand Let's see how much we can
eat and drink grandpa can eat
six desserts three
desserts and we
just
call and we go and eat a big good
dinner and this is
meditation and this
celebration
sometimes m you need to go and
celebrate your enlightenment as
if it already
happened and this becomes the cause of real
true
enlightenment
celebration of
don't do it every day because you
won't be able to meditate and
study I like some of my
friends say I like this practice
I do it every day
I say twice a
month 2
days a
day
don't
forget it's not 28 days of celebration and 2
days of
meditation on the contrary 2 days a month
celebrate as if you already
bu
28 days in a month Do the
work don't
[music]
confuse
You are already in
control of your body When you eat
early Imagine the rays of your body when
you go out and touch each
person they also
become and each of these people
becomes a
teacher and their bodies also change and they do
n't need to die anymore
celebrate
diligently twice a
good expensive
dinner do you want to know a secret
practice twice a month When you go to
celebrate that you will already be
for the hall next to
you
live we will pay for Here are those
guys please don't
say It's so
beautiful I told my
wife 2 weeks
ago as we go to a restaurant Let's
agree
we will pay for the table that is to the left of
us he says Okay let's go
we went to the
mask they sat us outside
and there was a special room where 20 people
can and they had a big
birthday celebration all the seats were taken I look
at my
wife I say I don't
know and she says you can't break a
promise we are
with  We did We haven't gone anywhere for a month a
few days
ago a few days ago she went there and
told me that they were very very
happy with the
news it's
hard to
get in I say I need a reservation
today that it's
[music]
busy can come
Well
celebrate in advance
because one day we will all become
boom Why not
[music]
celebrate what is it called when
the groom celebrates before the
wedding marriage marriage affairs party the
last book of
NGA is
called from very short
sentences and the next part which we
will study tomorrow morning
after
morning is the next
[music]
cha
paintings This is the middle of the wheel of
life I have good
news last week we completed the
book about the wheel of
life took 7
years a
beautiful city called the
city of Lviv
Singapore he completed the
book 25 pages very
complex very
deep the
book
will be next
year's course work 7
[music]
years this course will be released in November 24
years in this
year
we studied How to destroy the middle of the wheel of
life it's called three three
[music]
animals we will learn about this
tomorrow these three
animals represent your your mind
and emotions in your  нам я не сю
Цик и затра знам
как
врм се зат